<Form Description="Research" DateStarted="" DateFinished="" questionsPerPage="1" Class="surveyInlineBordered">
  <!-- This is an example of a question that sets an attribute when the "Yes" or "No" response is choosen
       the question is skipped when the attribute already exists -->
  <Items class="surveyInline">
    <Item Order="1" ItemResponse="" ItemScore="" RequiredMin="1" RequiredMax="1" Class="surveyQuestionCollapsible" Align="Horizontal" >
	 <PatientAttribute data_name="research" data_value="any" data_type="string" condition="notexists"/>
      <Description>
        <![CDATA[May we include you in our Research Database?]]>
      </Description>
	  <CollapsibleContent> <![CDATA[
           <p><b>DESCRIPTION:</b> You are invited to participate in a research database for current and future studies.
              Indicating "Yes" to the research database: 
              <ul> 
                 <li>Allows us to access information from your medical record (e.g. name, contact information, age, condition) to match you with research studies for which you may be eligible.</li>
                 <li>It does not obligate you to be a research participant, but allows us to contact you if we think you may be eligible for one of our research studies.</li> 
              </ul></p> 
           <p><b>TIME INVOLVEMENT:</b> Your participation will take approximately 5 minutes.</p> 
           <p><b>PAYMENTS:</b> You will not be paid to participate in this study.</p> 
           <p><b>PARTICIPANT'S RIGHTS:</b> If you have read this form and have decided to participate in this project,  
                 please understand your participation is voluntary and <u>you have the right to withdraw your consent
                 or discontinue participation at any time without penalty or loss of benefits to which you are  
                 otherwise entitled</u>. The alternative is not to participate. You have the right to refuse to answer
                 particular questions. Your individual privacy will be maintained in all published and written data  
                 resulting from the study.</p> 
           <p><b>RISKS AND BENEFITS:</b>  There is a small risk that people outside our research lab  
                 could learn this information, but we do our best to keep all your information confidential. The  
                 benefits which may reasonably be expected to result from this study are that you  
                 may be found to be a candidate for one or more studies conducted at our lab. We cannot and do not  
                 guarantee or promise that you will receive any benefits from this study. Your  
                 decision whether or not to participate in this study will not affect your medical care. </p> 
           <hr> 
           <h4><b>Authorization to Use Your Health Information for Research Purposes</b></h4>
           <p>....<i>this is just an example</i>...</p>
           <hr>
             <p><b>CONTACT INFORMATION:</b></p>
           <p>Questions, Concerns, or Complaints: If you have any questions, concerns or complaints about this research database, its procedures, risks and benefits, you should ask the Protocol Director, Dr. Sean Mackey at (650) 725-9636.</p> 
           <p>Independent Contact: If you are not satisfied with how this study is being conducted, or if you have any concerns, complaints, or general questions about the research or your rights as a participant, please contact the Stanford Institutional Review Board (IRB) to speak to someone independent of the research team at (650)-723-5244 or toll free at 1-866-680-2906. You can also write to the Stanford IRB, Stanford University, 3000 El Camino Real, Five Palo Alto Square, 4th Floor, Palo Alto, CA 94306.</p> 
           <p>Please print a copy of this form for your records.</p> 
]]>
	  </CollapsibleContent>
      <Responses>
        <Response Order="0" Type="radio" Class="registrySurvey" Description="Yes, your research team may contact me to discuss research opportunities">
          <Scores><Score value="0"/></Scores>
		  <SetPatientAttribute data_name="research" data_value="y"/>
		</Response>
        <Response Order="1" Type="radio" Class="registrySurvey" Description="No thank you">
          <Scores><Score value="1"/></Scores>
		  <SetPatientAttribute data_name="research" data_value="n"/>
        </Response>
		<Response Order="2" Type="radio" Class="registrySurvey" Description="Ask me again later">
          <Scores><Score value="2"/></Scores>
		</Response>
	  </Responses>
    </Item>
</Items>
</Form>
