<Form Description="TJA Outcomes Study Consent" questionsPerPage="1" >
  <Items>
    <Item Order="1" ref="consent" Class="surveyQuestionCollapsible">
      <PatientAttribute data_name="TJAOutcomesStudyConsent" data_value="any" condition="notexists"/>
<!--  <PatientAttribute data_name="age" data_value="17" condition="greaterthan"/> -->
      <Description>
<![CDATA[
  You are invited to participate in a research study on the outcomes of Total Joint Arthroplasty (TJA).
  <BR>
  Do you agree to allow us to use these questionnaires and your health information related to your Total Joint Arthroplasty for research purposes?
]]>
      </Description>
      <CollapsibleContent>
<![CDATA[
  <h3>Outcome of Total Joint Arthroplasty</h3>
  <p><b>DESCRIPTION:</b>
  You are invited to participate in a research study on the outcomes of Total Joint Arthroplasty (TJA).
  If you choose to participate, your health information related to your TJA, such as basic demographics
  (date of birth or death, name, email, insurance information), surgical details(including diagnoses,
  procedures, dates of service, admission, and discharge), x-rays, related physical examination records,
  and the answers to self-report questionnaires will be recorded in a secure database system.  The purpose
  of this database is to track your progress and the progress of other TJA patients to answer TJA research
  questions. The surveys are used for both research and for quality purposes, and are sent to both the
  California and the American Joint Replacement Registries. You will be asked to answer questionnaires prior
  to your surgery, and again 3 months, 1 year, and every other year after your surgery for the lifetime of
  the implant. You will receive the questionnaires via email, or on paper or a tablet upon entering the
  clinic for an appointment with your surgeon. You may opt out of receiving emails, or choose to not receive
  them at all.
  </p>
  <p><b>TIME INVOLVEMENT:</b>
  Your participation will take approximately 15-20 minutes.
  </p>
  <p><b>RISKS AND BENEFITS:</b>
  There are no risks associated with this study. The benefits which may reasonably be expected to result from this
  study are that your surgeon will be able to better track the progress of TJA patients, thus improving the quality
  of care of TJA patients, and advancing the field of Total Joint Arthroplasty. We cannot and do not guarantee or
  promise that you will receive any benefits from this study. Your decision whether or not to participate in this
  study will not affect your care.
  </p>
  <p><b>PAYMENTS:</b>
  You will not receive payment for your participation. 
  </p>
  <p>
  <b>SUBJECT'S RIGHTS:</b>
  If you have read this form and have decided to participate in this project, please understand your participation
  is voluntary and you have the right to withdraw your consent or discontinue participation at any time without
  penalty or loss of benefits to which you are otherwise entitled.  The alternative is not to participate. You have
  the right to refuse to answer particular questions. Your individual privacy will be maintained in all published
  and written data resulting from the study.
  </p>
  <p><b>CONTACT INFORMATION:</b></p>
  <p><i>Questions:</i>
  If you have any questions, concerns or complaints about this research, its procedures, risks and benefits,
  contact the Protocol Director, Dr. Stuart Goodman, (650) 721-7662.
  </p>
  <p><i>Independent Contact:</i>
  If you are not satisfied with how this study is being conducted, or if you have any concerns, complaints, or general
  questions about the research or your rights as a participant, please contact the Stanford Institutional Review Board (IRB)
  to speak to someone independent of the research team at (650)-723-2480 or toll free at 1-866-680-2906. You can also write
  to the Stanford IRB, Stanford University, 3000 El Camino Real, Five Palo Alto Square, 4th Floor, Palo Alto, CA 94306.  
  </p>
  <p><i>Appointment Contact:</i>
  If you need to change your appointment, please contact the clinic appointment line at (650) 723-5643.
  </p>
  <h3>Authorization To Use Your Health Information For Research Purposes</h3>
  <p><b>1. Introduction:</b></p>
  <p>
  Because information about you and your health is personal and private, it generally cannot be used in this research study
  without your written authorization. The form is intended to inform you about how your health information will be used or
  disclosed in the study. Your information will only be used in accordance with this authorization form and the informed
  consent form and as required or allowed by law. Please read it carefully.
  </p>
  <p><b>2. What is the purpose of this research study and how will my health information be utilized in the study?</b></p>
  <p>
  The purpose is to collect basic patient demographics, self-administered questionnaires, surgical data, related physical
  examination records, and x-rays in a password secured data base, in order to answer research questions posed by the
  investigator in regards to outcome of total joint replacement.
  </p>
  <p>
  None of the patients' individual responses or identifiers are ever used in publications. Instead patient responses remain
  anonymous and are aggregated as a group.
  </p>
  <p><b>3. Do I have to agree to this authorization?</b></p>
  <p>
  You do not have to agree to this authorization. But if you do not, you will not be able to participate in this research study.
  Agreeing to this the form is not a condition for receiving any medical care outside the study.
  </p>
  <p><b>4. If I agree, can I revoke it or withdraw from the research later?</b></p>
  <p>
  If you decide to participate, you are free to withdraw your authorization regarding the use and disclosure of your health
  information (and to discontinue any other participation in the study) at any time. After any revocation, your health
  information will no longer be used or disclosed in the study, except to the extent that the law allows us to continue using
  your information (e.g., necessary to maintain integrity of research). If you wish to revoke your authorization for the
  research use or disclosure of your health information in this study, you must write to:
  </p>
  <p>
  Drs. Derek Amanatullah, Nicholas Giori, Stuart B. Goodman, James Huddleston, William Maloney, Matthew Miller, Steven Woolson
  </p>
  <p>
  Department of Orthopaedic Surgery, 450 Broadway Street, M/C 6342, Redwood City, CA 94063 
  </p>
  <p><b>5. What Personal Information Will Be Used or Disclosed?</b></p>
  <p>
  Your health information related to this study, may be used or disclosed in connection with this research study, including,
  but not limited to, basic patient demographics, including Patient name, address, phone number, email address, date of birth,
  and insurance information, self-administered questionnaires, surgical data, related physical examination records, and x-rays. 
  </p>
  <p><b>6. Who May Use or Disclose the Information?</b></p>
  <p>
  The following parties are authorized to use and/or disclose your health information in connection with this research study:
  <ul>
  <li>The Protocol Director: Stuart Goodman, MD, PhD</li>
  <li>The Co-Investigators: Derek Amanatullah, MD; Nicholas Giori, MD; James Huddleston, MD; William Maloney, MD; Matthew Miller, MD; Steven Woolson, MD</li>
  <li>The Research team: Angela Bye; Katherine Hwang; Stanford Orthopaedic Fellows</li>
  <li>The Stanford University Administrative Panel on Human Subjects in Medical Research and any other unit of Stanford University as necessary.</li>
  </ul>
  </p>
  <p><b>7. Who May Receive / Use the Information?</b></p>
  <p>
  The parties listed in the preceding paragraph may disclose your health information to the following persons and organizations
  for their use in connection with this research study:
  <ul>
  <li>The Office for Human Research Protections in the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services</li>
  </ul>
  Your information may be re-disclosed by the recipients described above, if they are not required by law to protect the privacy of the information.
  </p>
  <p><b>8. When will my authorization expire?</b></p>
  <p>
  Your authorization for the use and/or disclosure of your health information will expire December 31, 2075.
  </p>
]]>
      </CollapsibleContent>
      <Responses>
        <!-- TotalJointCompleteHandler.java is expecting Yes to be Response Order 0 -->
        <Response Order="0" Type="radio" >
          <Description>Yes, I agree</Description>
          <Scores><Score value="0"/></Scores>
          <SetPatientAttribute data_name="TJAOutcomesStudyConsent" data_value="y"/>
        </Response>
        <Response Order="1" Type="radio" >
          <Description>No, I do not agree</Description>
          <Scores><Score value="1"/></Scores>
          <SetPatientAttribute data_name="TJAOutcomesStudyConsent" data_value="n"/>
        </Response>
      </Responses>
    </Item>

    <Item Order="2" Section="start">
      <ResponseValue xpath_query="//Item[@ref='consent']/@ItemResponse" data_value="0" condition="equal"/>
      <Description>Please check all that are applicable</Description>
      <Responses>
        <Response Order="1" Type="select" required="false">
          <ref>PARTICIPANT</ref>
          <item>
            <label>I am an adult participant in this study</label>
            <value>1</value>
            <onselect Type="Item" Where="Order" Value="3"/>
          </item>
          <item>
            <label>I am the parent or guardian granting permission for a child in this study (the use of "you" refers to "your child" or “your ward.”)</label>
            <value>2</value>
            <onselect Type="Item" Where="Order" Value="4"/>
          </item>
        </Response>
      </Responses>
    </Item>
    <Item Order="3" RequiredMin="0" Visible="false">
      <ResponseValue xpath_query="//Item[@ref='consent']/@ItemResponse" data_value="0" condition="equal"/>
      <Description>Enter your name</Description>
      <Responses>
        <Response ref="PATIENTNAME" Order="1" Type="input" required="true">
          <format> <datatype>text</datatype> <lines>1</lines> </format>
        </Response>
      </Responses>
    </Item>
    <Item Order="4" RequiredMin="0" Visible="false" Section="end">
      <ResponseValue xpath_query="//Item[@ref='consent']/@ItemResponse" data_value="0" condition="equal"/>
      <Description>Enter child's name</Description>
      <Responses>
        <Response ref="CHILDNAME" Order="1" Type="input" required="true">
          <format> <datatype>text</datatype> <lines>1</lines> </format>
        </Response>
      </Responses>
    </Item>

  </Items>
</Form>
