<Form Description="Pediatic Pain Research Consent" questionsPerPage="1" >
  <Items>
    <Item Order="1" ref="consent" Class="surveyQuestionCollapsible" >
      <PatientAttribute data_name="PedResearchConsent" data_value="any" condition="notexists"/>
      <Description>
<![CDATA[
  You are invited to participate in a research study to better understand pain conditions
  and psychosocial outcomes related to pediatric pain.
  <BR>
  Do you (the parent) agree to allow us to use these questionnaires and your health related information
  for this research study?
]]>
      </Description>
      <CollapsibleContent>
<![CDATA[
  <h3>Assessment of Pediatric Pain</h3>
  <p><b>DESCRIPTION:</b>
  You are invited to participate in a research study to better understand pain conditions and psychosocial
  outcomes related to pediatric pain. You and your child recently completed secure online questionnaires 
  before his/her initial appointment at the Pediatric Pain Clinic at Stanford Children’s Health. If you did 
  not have a chance to complete them before your appointment, you will use a Stanford-encrypted iPad to complete 
  the questionnaires now. Your responses help to inform patient care for our pediatric providers. The 
  questionnaires focused on demographics, medical history, and functioning (e.g., sleep, school, activity), 
  as well as thoughts, feelings, and behaviors related to the experience of pain for your child and family 
  (e.g., stress, sadness, and other pain concerns); however, at anytime, you have the right to refuse to 
  answer particular questions. If you agree to participate in the study after learning more from our 
  research team (e.g., examples of questions, frequency of questionnaires, how the study happens online, 
  how to stop participation if wanted at any time for any reason), you will be asked similar questions via 
  email three, six, nine, 12, and 24 months after your initial visit to the Pediatric Pain Clinic.
  </p>
  <p><b>STUDY PURPOSE:</b>
  With your family’s assistance, the investigators of this project hope to develop a better understanding 
  of medical, behavioral, and psychosocial factors associated with youth with chronic pain. This is a 
  project that may help us to learn more about: 1) coping, functioning, emotions, and levels of discomfort 
  (i.e., pain) at the time you are first evaluated at LPCH/Stanford, and 2) how these areas change over time 
  (e.g., if there is higher functioning, lower pain) in the outpatient clinic, or after receiving care from 
  the intensive rehabilitation treatment program.
  </p>
  <p><b>RISKS AND BENEFITS:</b>
  Other than needing time to complete the questionnaires, we do not anticipate any risks in this study. 
  The questionnaires might make you and your child notice the way that pain has affected your lives, 
  but we do not expect discomfort. We cannot and do not guarantee or promise that your child will receive 
  benefits from this study.
  </p>
  <p><b>TIME INVOLVEMENT:</b></p>
  <p>
  1. Pediatric Pain Management Clinic/Outpatient Clinic (PPMC): if you choose to follow-up with your child 
  in the Pediatric Pain Management Clinic after this first visit, and agree to participate in this research, 
  you will each be asked to complete similar questionnaires in three, six, nine, 12, and 24 months. Baseline 
  questionnaires will take approximately 45 minutes online, while subsequent questionnaires at follow-up will 
  approximately 30-45 minutes to complete online.
  </p>
  <p>
  2. Pediatric Rehabilitation Pain Program (PReP): if you agree to participate in this research, after your 
  child’s graduation from the intensive rehabilitation pain program, you will each complete similar questions 
  three, six, nine, 12 and 24 months after the program graduation. Baseline questionnaires will take approximately 
  45 minutes online, while subsequent questionnaires at follow-up will approximately 30-45 minutes to complete online.
  </p>
  <p><b>PAYMENTS:</b>
  There is no monetary reimbursement for participation in this study.
  </p>
  <p><b>PARTICIPANT’S RIGHTS:</b>
  If you have read this form and have decided to participate and to allow your child to participate 
  in this project, please understand you and your child’s participation is voluntary. The alternative 
  is not to participate. If participating, <u>you have the right to withdraw</u> you and your child’s consent 
  or discontinue participation <u>at any time</u> without penalty or loss of benefits to which you or your 
  child is otherwise entitled. You and your child’s individual privacy will be maintained in all 
  published data resulting from the study.
  </p>
  <p><b>CONTACT INFORMATION FOR QUESTIONS:</b>
  If you have any questions, concerns or complaints about this research, its procedures, risks and benefits, 
  contact the Protocol Director, Dr. Rashmi Bhandari at (650) 724-5333 or Protocol Co-Director, 
  Dr. Samantha Huestis at (650) 736-3482.
  </p>
  <p><b>WITHDRAWAL FROM STUDY:</b>
  The Protocol Director may also withdraw you and your child from the study without your consent for one or 
  more of the following reasons:
  <ul>
  <li>Failure to follow the instructions of the Protocol Director and study staff.</li>
  <li>The Protocol Director decides that continuing your participation could be harmful.</li>
  <li>The study is cancelled.</li>
  <li>Other administrative reasons.</li>
  <li>Unanticipated circumstances.</li>
  </ul>
  </p>

  <h3>AUTHORIZATION TO USE YOUR HEALTH INFORMATION FOR RESEARCH PURPOSES (HIPAA)</h3>
  <p>
  Because information about you and your health is personal and private, it generally cannot be used in 
  this research study without your written authorization.  If you sign this form, it will provide that 
  authorization. The form is intended to inform you about how your health information will be used or 
  disclosed in the study. Your information will only be used in accordance with this authorization form 
  and the informed consent form and as required or allowed by law. Please read it carefully before signing it.
  </p>
  <p><b>What is the purpose of this research study and how will my health information be utilized in the study?</b></p>
  <p>
  This study is meant to inform and enhance the quality of clinical care for pediatric patients with chronic 
  pain. Collecting information from the first Pain Clinic assessment (either via PPMC or PReP) through follow-up 
  treatments may clarify – through a patient- and family-centered lens – the Clinic’s understanding of how 
  physical well being, family functioning, and emotional health relate to pain and other medical domains. 
  Such clarification may then help to improve established interventions for chronic pain.
  </p>
  <p><b>Do I have to sign this authorization form?</b></p>
  <p>
  You do not have to sign this authorization form. But if you do not, you will not be able to participate in this 
  research study. Signing the form is not a condition for receiving any medical care outside the study.
  </p>
  <p><b>If I sign, can I revoke it or withdraw from the research later?</b></p>
  <p>
  If you decide to participate, you are free to withdraw your authorization regarding the use and disclosure of 
  your health information (and to discontinue any other participation in the study) at any time. After any 
  revocation, your health information will no longer be used or disclosed in the study, except to the extent 
  that the law allows us to continue using your information (e.g., necessary to maintain integrity of research). 
  If you wish to revoke your authorization for the research use or disclosure of your health information in 
  this study, please write to: Rashmi Bhandari, Ph.D. at rbhandar@stanford.edu.
  </p>
  <p><b>What Personal Information Will Be Used or Disclosed?</b></p>
  <p>
  Your health information related to this study, may be used or disclosed in connection with this research study, including,
  but not limited to, basic patient demographics, including Patient name, address, phone number, email address, date of birth,
  and insurance information, self-administered questionnaires, surgical data, related physical examination records, and x-rays. 
  </p>
  <p><b>What personal information will be obtained, used or disclosed?</b></p>
  <p>
  The health information we are looking to use includes protected medical information about you and your child. 
  We will need to know you and your child’s names, in addition to his or her: medical record number, birth date, 
  pain diagnosis and date this was diagnosed. We will also need to obtain and use your phone number(s), mailing 
  address, email address(es), and the number and type of interventions your child has received for pain management 
  (medications, physical therapy, psychotherapy, occupational therapy, massage, acupuncture, etc.). We will also 
  collect information on how your child is doing over time. Information collected will include how youth are 
  feeling and coping (pain level, stress, behaviors), and how they are functioning in school, at home, with 
  physical activity, and with friends. Similarly, we will also be asking the youth’s parent to provide responses 
  regarding observations of their child’s emotions, behaviors, and functioning at the initial visit and over time.
  </p>
  <p><b>Who may use or disclose the information?</b></p>
  <p>
  The following parties are authorized to use and/or disclose your health information in connection with this 
  research study:
  <ul>
  <li>The Protocol Director: Rashmi Bhandari, Ph.D</li>
  <li>The Protocol Co-Director: Samantha Huestis, Ph.D</li>
  <li>The Stanford University Administrative Panel on Human Subjects in Medical Research and any other unit of Stanford University as necessary</li>
  <li>Research Staff</li>
  </ul>
  </p>
  <p><b>Who may receive or use the information?</b></p>
  <p>
  The parties listed in the preceding paragraph may disclose your health information to the following persons and 
  organizations for their use in connection with this research study
  <ul>
  <li>The Office for Human Research Protections in the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services</li>
  </ul>
  Your information may be re-disclosed by the recipients described above, if they are not required by law to 
  protect the privacy of the information.
  </p>
  <p><b>When will my authorization expire?</b></p>
  <p>
  Your authorization for the use and/or disclosure of your health information will end on February 28, 2030 or 
  whenever the research project ends, whichever is earlier. 
  </p>
  <p><b>Will access to my medical record be limited during the study?</b></p>
  <p>
  To maintain the integrity of this research study, you may not have access to any health information developed 
  as part of this study until it is completed. At that point, you would have access to such health information 
  if it was used to make a medical or billing decision about you (i.e., if included in your official record). 
  </p>
]]>
      </CollapsibleContent>
      <Responses>
        <!-- Yes is expected to be Response Order 0 -->
        <Response Order="0" Type="radio" >
          <Description>Yes, I agree</Description>
          <Scores><Score value="0"/></Scores>
          <SetPatientAttribute data_name="PedResearchConsent" data_value="y"/>
        </Response>
        <Response Order="1" Type="radio" >
          <Description>No, I do not agree</Description>
          <Scores><Score value="1"/></Scores>
          <SetPatientAttribute data_name="PedResearchConsent" data_value="n"/>
        </Response>
        <Response Order="2" Type="radio" >
          <Description>Ask me again later</Description>
          <Scores><Score value="2"/></Scores>
        </Response>
      </Responses>
    </Item>

    <Item Order="2" ref="assent" Class="surveyQuestionCollapsible" >
      <ResponseValue xpath_query="//Item[@ref='consent']/@ItemResponse" data_value="0" condition="equal"/>
      <PatientAttribute data_name="age" data_value="7" condition="greaterthan"/>
      <Description>
<![CDATA[
  Does the child also agree to allow us to use these questionnaires and your health related information
  for this research study?
]]>
      </Description>
      <CollapsibleContent>
<![CDATA[
  <h3>Assessment of Pediatric Pain</h3>
  <p><b>1. What will happen to me in this study?</b></p>
  <p>
  You are invited to participate in a research study to better understand pain conditions and psychosocial 
  outcomes related to pediatric pain. Our team wants to understand how pain affects what you think, how you 
  feel, and where you do things in your day-to-day life. We hope to improve how we evaluate (ask about) and 
  treat (help) pain by learning from you and your family. Your parent already received an email before this 
  first visit to our Pain Clinic, and you both were asked to answer questions online. Thank you for doing that!
  </p>
  <p>
  If you agree to be part of this study, we will use your responses to improve how we help kids and families 
  like yours in the future. You will also be asked to answer some of the same questions in 3, 6, 9, 12, and 
  24 months. At anytime, you have the right to refuse to answer particular questions. This study is not an 
  experiment, so you will not be asked to do anything but answer questions online. We are happy to talk to 
  you about the questions if you wish to. 
  </p>
  <p><b>TIME INVOLVEMENT:</b></p>
  <p>
  1. Pediatric Pain Management Clinic/Outpatient Clinic (PPMC): if you choose to follow-up with your child 
  in the Pediatric Pain Management Clinic after this first visit, and agree to participate in this research, 
  you will each be asked to complete similar questionnaires online in three, six, nine, 12, and 24 months. 
  Baseline questionnaires will take approximately 45 minutes, while subsequent questionnaires at follow-up 
  will approximately 30-45 minutes to complete online. 
  </p>
  <p>
  2. Pediatric Rehabilitation Pain Program (PReP): if you agree to participate in this research, after your 
  child’s graduation from the intensive rehabilitation pain program, you will each complete similar questions 
  three, six, nine, 12 and 24 months after the program graduation online. Baseline questionnaires will take 
  approximately 45 minutes, while subsequent questionnaires at follow-up will approximately 30-45 minutes to 
  complete online.
  </p>
  <p><b>2. Can anything bad happen to me?</b></p>
  <p>
  It is up to you to decide if you want to participate. Helping with this study will not cause anything bad 
  to happen to you. We do want you to be honest in answering the questions, and no one but us will know your 
  answers. If you do not understand some questions, or some questions make you feel worried or sad, our team 
  will be happy to talk to you.
  </p>
  <p><b>3. Can anything good happen to me?</b></p>
  <p>
  We cannot and do not guarantee or promise that you will receive benefits from this study. However, being 
  part of our study may help you feel good about being involved in research for kids with chronic pain. 
  If you agree to do this study, you will express how you feel about your pain, and what you do about it. 
  We will study and share what we learned from you to help other kids with pain in the future, and can share 
  those results with you if you would like. Your participation in this study will give us information that can 
  then be used to help providers improve the assessments (ratings) they do, and the interventions (treatments) 
  they offer to reduce the impact of pain on your life. 
  </p>
  <p><b>4. Do I have other choices?</b></p>
  <p>
  Of course! Your participation in this study is your choice, and you can stop being in this study at any time. 
  The other choice is not to participate, and this is okay with us. It will not affect how we take care of you 
  at Stanford.
  </p>
  <p><b>5. Will anyone know I am in the study?</b></p>
  <p>
  Your participation in this study will be kept confidential (secret). No one but our pediatric research team 
  will know that you are participating. Even your parents will not know how you answer questions, unless you 
  want them to, or we have to tell them something to keep you healthy.
  </p>
  <p><b>6. Who can I talk to about the study?</b></p>
  <p>
  If you have any questions about the study or any problems with the study you can contact the Protocol Director, 
  Dr. Rashmi Bhandari at (650) 724-5333. You can also call Co-Protocol Director, 
  Dr. Samantha Huestis at (650) 736-3482.
  </p>
  <p>
  If you have questions about the study but want to talk to someone else who is not a part of the study, you can 
  call the Stanford Institutional Review Board (IRB) at (650)-723-5244 or toll free at 1-866-680-2906.
  </p>
  <p><b>7. What if I do not want to do this?</b></p>
  <p>
  Your participation in this study is voluntary, meaning you can choose to be in the study or not. It is 100% up 
  to you and your parents. Even if you decide to do the study and then change your mind, that is okay. 
  Our medical team will continue to work with you and help you if you need it.
  </p>
]]>
      </CollapsibleContent>
      <Responses>
        <!-- Yes is expected to be Response Order 0 -->
        <Response Order="0" Type="radio" >
          <Description>Yes, I agree</Description>
          <Scores><Score value="0"/></Scores>
          <SetPatientAttribute data_name="PedResearchAssent" data_value="y"/>
        </Response>
        <Response Order="1" Type="radio" >
          <Description>No, I do not agree</Description>
          <Scores><Score value="1"/></Scores>
          <SetPatientAttribute data_name="PedResearchAssent" data_value="n"/>
        </Response>
      </Responses>
    </Item>

    <Item Order="3" required="false">
      <PatientAttribute data_name="surveyEmailAddress" data_value="any" condition="exists"/>
      <ResponseValue xpath_query="//Item[@ref='consent']/@ItemResponse" data_value="0" condition="equal"/>
      <ResponseValue xpath_query="//Item[@ref='assent']/@ItemResponse" data_value="1" condition="notequal"/>
      <Description>
<![CDATA[
  <p>Thank you for agreeing to participate in the research study on the Assessment of Pediatric Pain.</p>
  <p>A copy of the Research Consent and Youth Assent forms and  will be sent to you via email.</p>
]]>
      </Description>
      <Responses> 
        <Response Order="1" Type="select1" required="false">
        </Response>
      </Responses>
    </Item>

    <Item Order="4" required="false">
      <PatientAttribute data_name="surveyEmailAddress" data_value="any" condition="notexists"/>
      <ResponseValue xpath_query="//Item[@ref='consent']/@ItemResponse" data_value="0" condition="equal"/>
      <ResponseValue xpath_query="//Item[@ref='assent']/@ItemResponse" data_value="1" condition="notequal"/>
      <Description>
<![CDATA[
  <p>Thank you for agreeing to participate in the research study on the Assessment of Pediatric Pain.</p>
  <p>A copy of the Research Consent and Youth Assent forms can be obtained from the front desk.</p>
]]>
      </Description>
      <Responses> 
        <Response Order="1" Type="select1" required="false">
        </Response>
      </Responses>
    </Item>

  </Items>
</Form>
