<Form Description="Research Consent" questionsPerPage="1" >
  <Items>
    <Item Order="1">
      <PatientAttribute data_name="cfsConsent" data_value="any" condition="notexists"/>
      <Description>
<![CDATA[
  <p>Dear Patient,</p>
  <p>Welcome to the Stanford Clinical Intake Questionnaire for Patients with Chronic Unexplained Illnesses.
  Please take your time answering the following questions. This is a questionnaire we will use to get an
  approximate picture of your health and how ME/CFS has affected you. This questionnaire will likely take
  10-20 minutes to complete. If you are unsure how to answer a question, give it your best effort.
  </p>
  <p>If at any point you have questions or require help, please feel free to contact our research coordinator,
  Jill Anderson, at 650-723-9711 or janders5@stanford.edu.
  </p>
]]>
      </Description>
      <Responses>
        <Response Order="1" Type="select1" required="false">
        <ref>intro</ref>
        </Response>
      </Responses>
    </Item>

    <Item Order="2">
      <PatientAttribute data_name="cfsConsent" data_value="any" condition="notexists"/>
      <Description>
<![CDATA[
  <p>We would like to find out how you are feeling before your visit with us. The next few pages contain some
  questionnaires that will help us prepare for your visit and tell us more about your health. We also maintain
  a database of the information about our patients in order to learn more about your health and strengthen our
  clinical practice.
  </p>
  <p><b>By completing the questions, you are confirming your consent to be included in our
  secure patient database.</b> The full consent form, available below, or at the front desk at the clinic,
  describes what information we collect, how we will use the information and how we will protect your information.
  </p>
  <p><b>Being included in the data collection does not require you to make additional visits and there is no
  experimental intervention. Additionally, your identity is never used or shared when we study the information collected.</b>
  </p>
]]>
      </Description>
      <Responses>
        <Response Order="1" Type="collapsible">
          <label>Consent Form</label>
          <CollapsibleContent>
<![CDATA[

  <p><b>CONSENT</b></p>
  <p><b>For Collection of Medical Information</b></p>
  <p><b>DESCRIPTION:</b> You are invited to participate in a research study on chronic unexplained illnesses.
  From the information collected and studied in this project we hope to learn more about the causes and effects
  of chronic unexplained illnesses.
  </p>
  <p><b>PROCEDURES:</b> With your permission, we would like to collect health information about you, including
  your responses to several questionnaires, information about your general health (results from blood tests,
  medications, physical exam findings) related to medical treatments and care you receive. The questionnaires
  and assessments will be administered online and at your clinic visits. We would like to collect this information
  about you after each medical visit you have for as long as you are treated at a Stanford Clinic or hospital.
  This study does not involve any treatment  just the collection and study of medical information.
  </p>
  <p><b>RISKS AND BENEFITS:</b> Risks of participating in this research are minimal and consist of possible
  breaches of confidentiality. Though we make every effort to protect your health information, there is always
  a small risk that your information will be accessed by unauthorized persons, especially if a paper forms are
  mailed or faxed. You will not receive any direct benefit from participation. We cannot and do not guarantee
  or promise that you will receive any benefits from this study.
  </p>
  <p><b>TIME INVOLVEMENT:</b> Your participation in this study will require that you complete an intake questionnaire
  consisting of a health history questionnaire and several other questionnaires and assessments, which may take
  anywhere from 5 minutes to 30 minutes to complete, as well as a shorter version of the questionnaire which will
  be administered at or before your follow-up clinic appointments. The shorter version of the questionnaire will
  take 30 minutes or less to complete. We will ask you to complete the shorter questionnaire at your follow-up
  appointments for the duration of the study, which is anticipated to be ten years. You will not have any further
  time involvement in this study following the completion of the project. If you agree to participate, you will
  complete the questionnaires securely online or you may also request a paper copy of the questionnaires. If you
  agree to participate, we will collect medical information from your medical record after each visit, which does
  not involve any direct participation by you.
  </p>
  <p><b>PAYMENTS:</b> You will not be paid to participate in this study.
  </p> 
  <p><b>PARTICIPANT'S RIGHTS:</b> If you have read this form and have decided to participate in this project, please
  understand your participation is voluntary and you have the right to withdraw your consent or discontinue
  participation at any time without penalty or loss of benefits to which you are otherwise entitled. You have the
  right to refuse to answer particular questions. Your identity will not be disclosed in any published and written
  material resulting from the study.
  </p>
  <p><b>Authorization to Use Your Health Information for Research Purposes</b>
  </p> 
  <p>Because information about you and your health is personal and private, it generally cannot be used in this
  research study without your written authorization. If you participate in this study, your participation will
  provide that authorization. The form is intended to inform you about how your health information will be used
  or disclosed in the study. Your information will only be used in accordance with this authorization form and
  the informed consent form and as required or allowed by law. Please read it carefully before participating.
  </p>
  <p><b>What is the purpose of this research study and how will my health information be utilized in the study?</b>
  </p> 
  <p>The purpose of this project is to study the causes and effects of chronic unexplained illnesses. Your responses
  to several questionnaires and you medical information will be used to learn more about chronic unexplained illnesses.
  </p>
  <p><b>Do I have to sign this authorization form?</b>
  </p> 
  <p>You do not have to sign this authorization form or participate in this research.
  </p>
  <p><b>If I agree to participate, can I revoke my permission or withdraw from the research later?</b>
  </p>
  <p>If you decide to participate, you are free to withdraw your authorization regarding the use and disclosure of
  your health information (and to discontinue any other participation in the study) at any time. After any revocation,
  your health information will no longer be used or disclosed in the study, except to the extent that the law allows
  us to continue using your information (e.g., necessary to maintain integrity of research). If you wish to revoke
  your authorization for the research use or disclosure of your health information in this study, you must do so in
  writing. Please provide the written withdrawal to Dr. Montoya’s research team at 1000 Welch Road, Suite 202, Palo Alto, CA 94304.
  </p>
  <p><b>What Personal Information Will Be Used or Disclosed?</b>
  </p> 
  <p>We will be looking at the following categories of health information, where * denotes embedded identifiers:
  * laboratory and pathology test results with embedded identifiers, coded diagnoses and procedures,
  * clinical records with embedded identifiers,
  * images and imaging reports with embedded identifiers,
  * demographics with embedded identifiers.
  We will be obtaining and using the following protected health information: laboratory and pathology test results
  with embedded identifiers, clinical records with embedded identifiers, images and imaging reports with embedded
  identifiers, demographics with embedded identifiers (names, telephone numbers, address (all geographic subdivisions
  smaller than a state), dates more precise than year only, e.g. date of birth or death, date of service, diagnosis,
  admission, electronic mail addresses, medical record numbers).
  </p>
  <p><b>Who May Use or Disclose the Information?</b>
  </p> 
  <p>The following parties are authorized to use and/or disclose your health information in connection with this research study:
    <ul> 
      <li>The Protocol Director</li>
      <li>The Stanford University Administrative Panel on Human Subjects in Medical Research and any other unit of Stanford University as necessary</li> 
      <li>Research Staﬀ working on this project</li>
    </ul>
  </p> 
  <p><b>Who May Receive or Use the Information?</b>
  The parties listed in the preceding paragraph may disclose your health information to the following persons and
  organizations for their use in connection with this research study:
  </p> 
    <ul> 
      <li>The Oﬃce for Human Research Protections in the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services</li> 
    </ul> 
  <p>Your information may be re-disclosed by the recipients described above,
  if they are not required by law to protect the privacy of the information.
  </p> 
  <p><b>When will my authorization expire?</b>
  </p> 
  <p>Your authorization for the use and/or disclosure of your health information will end on December 31, 2100.
  </p>
  <p><b>CONTACT INFORMATION:</b></p> 
  <p>Questions, Concerns, or Complaints: If you have any questions, concerns or complaints about this research study,
  its procedures, risks and benefits, or alternative courses of treatment, you should ask Dr. Montoya’s research
  coordinator Tullia Lieb, at 650-723-8126.  You should also contact her at any time if you feel you have been
  hurt by being a part of this study.
  </p>
  <p>Independent Contact: If you are not satisfied with how this study is being conducted, or if you have any concerns,
  complaints, or general questions about the research or your rights as a participant, please contact the Stanford
  Institutional Review Board (IRB) to speak to someone independent of the research team at (650)-723-5244 or toll
  free at 1-866-680-2906. You can also write to the Stanford IRB, Stanford University, 3000 El Camino Real,
   Five Palo Alto Square, 4th Floor, Palo Alto, CA 94306.
   </p>
   <p>Please feel free to print out a copy of this form for your records. It is for you to keep.
   </p>
   <p>If you agree to participate in this research, please complete the following questionnaire.
   </p>
]]>
          </CollapsibleContent>
        </Response>
        <Response Order="2" Type="select1" required="true">
          <ref>CFSCONSENT</ref>
          <item>
            <label>Yes, I agree to participate in this research</label>
            <value>1</value>
          </item>
          <item>
            <label>No, I do not want to participate in this research</label>
            <value>2</value>
          </item>
        </Response>
      </Responses>
    </Item>

    <Item Order="3">
      <PatientAttribute data_name="surveyEmailAddress" data_value="any" data_type="string" condition="notexists"/>
      <ResponseValue xpath_query="//Response[ref='CFSCONSENT']/item[value=1]/@selected" data_value="true" condition="equal"/>
      <Description>
<![CDATA[
  <p>Your email address is required to receive a copy of the consent and follow-up research communications</p>
]]>
      </Description>
      <Responses>
        <Response Order="1" ref="email" Type="input" required="false">
          <label>Email Address</label>
          <format>
            <datatype>text</datatype>
            <lines>1</lines>
            <charwidth>80</charwidth>
          </format>
        </Response>
        <Response Order="2" ref="sendForm" Type="select1" required="true">
          <item>
            <label>Yes, email the consent form to the address entered above</label>
            <value>1</value>
          </item>
          <item>
            <label>No, do not email the consent form</label>
            <value>2</value>
          </item>
        </Response>
      </Responses>
    </Item>

    <Item Order="4">
      <PatientAttribute data_name="surveyEmailAddress" data_value="any" data_type="string" condition="exists"/>
      <ResponseValue xpath_query="//Response[ref='CFSCONSENT']/item[value=1]/@selected" data_value="true" condition="equal"/>
      <ResponseValue xpath_query="//Item[@Order='3']/@ItemResponse" condition="notexists"/>
      <Description>
<![CDATA[
  <p>Do you want a copy of the consent form sent to your email address?</p> 
]]>
      </Description>
      <Responses>
        <Response Order="1" ref="sendForm" Type="select1" required="true">
          <item>
            <label>Yes, email the consent form</label>
            <value>1</value>
          </item>
          <item>
            <label>No, do not email the consent form</label>
            <value>2</value>
          </item>
        </Response>
      </Responses>
    </Item>
  </Items>
 </Form>
