<Form Description="Research" DateStarted="" DateFinished="" questionsPerPage="1" Class="surveyInlineBordered">
  <Items class="surveyInline">
    <Item Order="1" ItemResponse="" ItemScore="" RequiredMin="1" RequiredMax="1" Class="surveyQuestionCollapsible" Align="Horizontal" >
   <PatientAttribute data_name="research" data_value="any" data_type="string" condition="notexists"/>
      <Description>
        <![CDATA[Would you like to be contacted about future educational, group, or research opportunities?]]>
      </Description>
    <CollapsibleContent> <![CDATA[
          <p>Many of the physicians here at the Stanford Children's Pain Clinic conduct research to learn more about chronic pain and
          develop new therapies to treat pain.</p>
          <p>We would like to include you in our Research Database so that we may contact you regarding
          current or future research studies.</p>
          <p>Indicating "Yes" to the research database:
            <ul>
              <li> Allows us to access information from your medical record (e.g. name, contact information, age, pain condition) to match you with research studies for which you may be eligible. </li>
              <li> It does not obligate you to be a research participant, but allows us to contact you if we think you may be eligible for one of our research studies.</li>
              <li> You may contact the research team at any time to be removed from our contact list.</li>
            </ul>
          </p>
          <p>You may choose not to participate, or not to speak with us further about our research at any time, without affecting your medical treatment. 
          Completing this form is voluntary and is not related to your medical appointment. All the information we collect will remain as confidential as
          possible as required by law. We will never share your personal identifying information outside of the Stanford School of Medicine Researchers
          who are approved to access this information.
          <p>For general information about participant rights, contact 1-866-680-2906.</p>
]]>
    </CollapsibleContent>
      <Responses>
        <Response Order="0" Type="radio" Class="registrySurvey" Description="Yes, your research team may contact me to discuss research opportunities">
          <Scores><Score value="0"/></Scores>
      <SetPatientAttribute data_name="research" data_value="y"/>
    </Response>
        <Response Order="1" Type="radio" Class="registrySurvey" Description="No thank you">
          <Scores><Score value="1"/></Scores>
      <SetPatientAttribute data_name="research" data_value="n"/>
        </Response>
    <Response Order="2" Type="radio" Class="registrySurvey" Description="Ask me again later">
          <Scores><Score value="2"/></Scores>
    </Response>
    </Responses>
    </Item>
</Items>
</Form>
